

Teejay Hidalgo

Backend Web Developer



Summary

I am a professional back-end developer with 7 year experience in creating websites. Proficient knowledge of the back-end programming language/framework. I have a good understanding of front-end web technologies like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and communicate well with front end developers. I am able to manage a hosting environment, including database administration as well as scaling applications to handle load changes. With experience in version control, such as Git. I am currently looking for a company or freelance job where I can continue to grow and learn as a web developer and software engineer.



Experience

2011-07 -2017-05

Senior Software Engineer

Sevenworks Inc.

- · Writing, maintaining and enhancing program code
- · Creating, maintaining, and enhancing databases
- Testing, debugging, diagnosing and correcting errors and bugs in an application
- Managing and working with a small team to ensure that the project specification is met and is delivered in a timely manner
- Communicating and coordinating with project managers and clients during the development lifecycle for concerns requiring technical knowledge
- Reviewing current system or process and presenting ideas for improvements
- · Researching and integrating APIs, plugins and extensions
- Researching and identifying technology requirements, proposing process and solutions
- Preparing system specifications, flow charts, timeline, scope and limitations
- Integrating user-facing elements developed by front-end developers with server side logic
- Worked closely with Designers, Customer Support and QA to develop suite of web tools for internal and external users
- Worked closely with product managers, editorial and business partners to understand software requirements

2009-11 -2011-04

Junior Developer

Ivertise Multimedia Designs Corporation

- · Setup and configuration of the framework and database for new projects
- · Writing new codes for projects requiring new functions and enhancements
- · Analysis of client requirement and propose solutions and enhancements
- Reviewing client requests and providing man hours estimate for the customization
- Maintenance, enhancement and create backup of the website and database





Address

Las Pinas City Metro Manila Philippines

Phone

09088623402

E-mail

teejay.hidalgo@gmail.com

Date of birth

1988-02-14

www

http://antariprince.com/

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/teejayhidalgo-antariprince/



HD

••••

Javascript

Jquery

MySql

••••

Debugging

••••

Git

Codeigniter

••••

 Testing, debugging and troubleshooting the system to ensure the 	Laravel
applications perform to specification	••
Contributed in the development of an internal CMS framework for the	Wordpress
company	•••
Creating user manual	Prestashop
Internship	•••
Novare Technologies	Poststron
Developed a Bug Tracking Mobile Application (Mobile Mantis) for	Bootstrap
Blackberry devices utilizing both API provided by RIM (research in motion	· ·
and API by Mantis Connect.	AWS
	••
Education	HTML5
De La Salle University	••
Bachelor of Science in Information and Communication Technology	CSS3
Management	• •
• GPA 2.7	Web Scraping
	•••
Portfolio	Photoshop
https://share.autoriaria.autoriaria.autoriaria.autoriaria	1 Hotoshop
https://shop.antariprince.com/index.php	
https://booksforcast.com/	
https://openhouse.antariprince.com/	
https://jdc.booksforcast.com/	
https://ecom.antariprince.com/	

2008-09 -2008-12

2005-05 -2009-04

Reading

Dota 2

Cooking

Travelling

Learning to Guitar

Watching Movies and American Series

Badminton, Table Tennis, Tennis, Gym, Jogging, Meditation